{
	"name": "category-chapter-30-tag-multiple-choice",
	"cards": [
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-30-tag-multiple-choice-card-1",
			"front": "The phrenic nerves control the diaphragm and exit the spinal cord at:\n\nA. C3, C4, and C5.\nB. C3 and C4.\nC. C1, C2, and C3.\nD. C1 and C2.\nSee Mechanics of Ventilation",
			"back": "C3, C4, and C5."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-30-tag-multiple-choice-card-2",
			"front": "A simple pneumothorax:\n\nA. is caused by penetrating chest trauma.\nB. is commonly caused by blunt chest trauma.\nC. often has a nontraumatic cause.\nD. heals on its own without any treatment.\nSee Complications and Management of Chest Injuries",
			"back": "is commonly caused by blunt chest trauma."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-30-tag-multiple-choice-card-3",
			"front": "A patient who presents with profound cyanosis following a chest injury:\n\nA. has most likely experienced a ruptured aorta.\nB. is most likely experiencing severe blood loss.\nC. requires prompt ventilation and oxygenation.\nD. should be placed in Trendelenburg’s position.\nSee Injuries of the Chest",
			"back": "requires prompt ventilation and oxygenation."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-30-tag-multiple-choice-card-4",
			"front": "If a person’s tidal volume decreases, but his or her respiratory rate remains unchanged:\n\nA. minute volume will decrease.\nB. minute volume will increase.\nC. minute volume will remain unchanged.\nD. excess carbon dioxide will be eliminated.\nSee Mechanics of Ventilation",
			"back": "minute volume will decrease."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-30-tag-multiple-choice-card-5",
			"front": "Which of the following organs or structures does not reside within the mediastinum?\n\nA. Trachea\nB. Vena cavae\nC. Esophagus\nD. Lungs\nSee Anatomy and Physiology",
			"back": "Lungs"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-30-tag-multiple-choice-card-6",
			"front": "A rapid, irregular pulse following blunt trauma to the chest is most suggestive of a:\n\nA. myocardial contusion.\nB. pericardial tamponade.\nC. ruptured aorta.\nD. tension pneumothorax.\nSee Other Chest Injuries",
			"back": "myocardial contusion."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-30-tag-multiple-choice-card-7",
			"front": "If a patient with a chest injury only inhales small amounts of air per breath, he or she:\n\nA. often breathes at a slower rate because of lung damage caused by the injury.\nB. will eliminate more carbon dioxide than if he or she were breathing deeply.\nC. must increase his or her respiratory rate to maintain adequate minute volume.\nD. will maintain adequate minute volume if his or her respiratory rate stays the same.\nSee Mechanics of Ventilation",
			"back": "must increase his or her respiratory rate to maintain adequate minute volume."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-30-tag-multiple-choice-card-8",
			"front": "When a person is lying supine at the end of exhalation, the diaphragm:\n\nA. contracts and flattens inferiorly.\nB. is less prone to penetrating trauma.\nC. descends below the level of the navel.\nD. might rise as high as the nipple line.\nSee Anatomy and Physiology",
			"back": "might rise as high as the nipple line."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-30-tag-multiple-choice-card-9",
			"front": "Subcutaneous emphysema is an indication that:\n\nA. at least half of one lung has completely collapsed.\nB. air is escaping into the chest wall from a damaged lung.\nC. your patient is experiencing a pericardial tamponade.\nD. blood is slowly accumulating within the tissue of the lung.\nSee Complications and Management of Chest Injuries",
			"back": "air is escaping into the chest wall from a damaged lung."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-30-tag-multiple-choice-card-10",
			"front": "A flail chest occurs when:\n\nA. a segment of the chest wall is detached from the thoracic cage.\nB. more than three ribs are fractured on the same side of the chest.\nC. a segment of fractured ribs bulges during the inhalation phase.\nD. multiple ribs are fractured on both sides of the thoracic cage.\nSee Complications and Management of Chest Injuries",
			"back": "a segment of the chest wall is detached from the thoracic cage."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-30-tag-multiple-choice-card-11",
			"front": "The thoracic cavity is separated from the abdominal cavity by the:\n\nA. anterior rib cage.\nB. costovertebral angle.\nC. diaphragm.\nD. intercostal margin.\nSee Anatomy and Physiology",
			"back": "diaphragm."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-30-tag-multiple-choice-card-12",
			"front": "Pneumothorax is defined as:\n\nA. accumulation of air between the lungs.\nB. blood collection within the pleural space.\nC. blood collection within the lung tissue.\nD. accumulation of air in the pleural space.\nSee Complications and Management of Chest Injuries",
			"back": "accumulation of air in the pleural space."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-30-tag-multiple-choice-card-13",
			"front": "Irritation or damage to the pleural surfaces that causes sharp chest pain during inhalation is called:\n\nA. dyspnea.\nB. pneumothorax.\nC. pneumonitis.\nD. pleurisy.\nSee Injuries of the Chest",
			"back": "pleurisy."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-30-tag-multiple-choice-card-14",
			"front": "Elevation of the rib cage during inhalation occurs when:\n\nA. the diaphragm descends.\nB. the intercostal muscles contract.\nC. abdominal contents descend.\nD. intrathoracic pressure decreases.\nSee Mechanics of Ventilation",
			"back": "the intercostal muscles contract."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-30-tag-multiple-choice-card-15",
			"front": "When assessing a patient with a hemothorax, you will most likely find:\n\nA. jugular venous engorgement.\nB. signs and symptoms of shock.\nC. ipsilateral tracheal deviation.\nD. distant or muffled heart tones.\nSee Complications and Management of Chest Injuries",
			"back": "signs and symptoms of shock."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-30-tag-multiple-choice-card-16",
			"front": "The ________ nerves supply the diaphragm.\n\nA. intercostal\nB. vagus\nC. phrenic\nD. costal\nSee Mechanics of Ventilation",
			"back": "phrenic"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-30-tag-multiple-choice-card-17",
			"front": "Signs and symptoms of a tension pneumothorax include all of the following, except:\n\nA. altered mental status.\nB. collapsed jugular veins.\nC. profound cyanosis.\nD. unilaterally absent breath sounds.\nSee Complications and Management of Chest Injuries",
			"back": "collapsed jugular veins."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-30-tag-multiple-choice-card-18",
			"front": "Hemoptysis is defined as:\n\nA. vomiting blood.\nB. abnormal blood clotting.\nC. blood in the pleural space.\nD. coughing up blood.\nSee Injuries of the Chest",
			"back": "coughing up blood."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-30-tag-multiple-choice-card-19",
			"front": "An open pneumothorax is:\n\nA. a fractured rib that perforates the tissue of the lung surface.\nB. extreme pleural pressure that causes the lung to rupture.\nC. an open chest wound through which air moves during breathing.\nD. the entry of air into the pleural space from a perforated lung.\nSee Complications and Management of Chest Injuries",
			"back": "an open chest wound through which air moves during breathing."
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-30-tag-multiple-choice-card-20",
			"front": "Patients with rib fractures will commonly:\n\nA. take a series of deep breaths.\nB. prefer to lie in a supine position.\nC. breathe rapidly and shallowly.\nD. develop a sucking chest wound.\nSee Complications and Management of Chest Injuries",
			"back": "breathe rapidly and shallowly."
		}
	],
	"category": {
		"value": "chapter-30",
		"label": "Chapter 30"
	},
	"tags": [
		{
			"value": "multiple-choice",
			"label": "Multiple Choice"
		}
	]
}